<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>solutions on DUAN DAHAI</title><link>https://www.duandahai.com/categories/solutions/</link><description>Recent content in solutions on DUAN DAHAI</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.duandahai.com/categories/solutions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Use VBA to run a Powershell</title><link>https://www.duandahai.com/posts/en/20221215-call-powershell-in-vba/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.duandahai.com/posts/en/20221215-call-powershell-in-vba/</guid><description>In an auto task VBA tool, I find that instead of VBA scripts,
call a powershell file can use some more effective solutions.
So I share an example that call a Powershell file in VBA.
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 Dim command As String Dim wsh As Object Dim result As Long command = &amp;#34;powershell -NoProfile -ExecutionPolicy Unrestricted &amp;#34; command = command &amp;amp; &amp;#34;C:¥yourPowershellFile.</description></item><item><title>Use custom domain to send emails by AWS SES</title><link>https://www.duandahai.com/posts/en/20221205-use-custom-domain-on-aws-ses/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.duandahai.com/posts/en/20221205-use-custom-domain-on-aws-ses/</guid><description>In most applications, you may need SMTP service for send some system notifications, you need not hosting your own SMTP server, because it is much more difficult to do reliably than to use a third-party provider.
In this article, I will show how I use the AWS SES on my own domain.
Get a domain You can get one from onamae, also you can get one from godaddy. But I think if you manage your applications on AWS, you should consider the AWS Route 53.</description></item><item><title>Simply setup spark in windows OS</title><link>https://www.duandahai.com/posts/en/20221028-setup-spark-in-windows/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.duandahai.com/posts/en/20221028-setup-spark-in-windows/</guid><description>When you want to start learning about spark and try to write or run some scripts, you needn&amp;rsquo;t spent time to search the integration solution about spark environment, you needn&amp;rsquo;t confuse that you don&amp;rsquo;t have a linux environment or a cloud service account. Just take the integrated spark environment into your own PC, only one step setup, then you can use it. and even you needn&amp;rsquo;t to install anything in your PC.</description></item><item><title>One solution for real time monitoring abnormal data in database</title><link>https://www.duandahai.com/posts/en/20210607-real-time-monitoring-db/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.duandahai.com/posts/en/20210607-real-time-monitoring-db/</guid><description> The design of monitoring system In some case we need monitor application&amp;rsquo;s latest data in database on time. We could built a monitoring system out of the application.
In this case, to handle a large of new data per second with high-performance, we can build the monitoring system like this:
Output new inserted data into monitoring system database by trigger Output new inserted data into Queque(like AWS SQS) by trigger Get new data from Queque and execute your monitoring app in dynamic multiple process</description></item></channel></rss>